# Joshua Bell

65 Beri Dr, Asheville, NC 28806 joshua.bell.828@gmail.com (828) 222-8787

## **Professional Summary**

Tech Tinkerer. Currently addicted to full-Stack developing and everything Web3. Crypto and Blockchain enthusiast. I love working with bleeding-edge technology and helping decentralize the web! I have extensive knowledge of a wide range of computer science disciplines. I also have a vast amount of experience dealing with customer service.

## My Honed Skillset

I love computer science so my tech stack is pretty vast. Here's some of the things I most actively engage with currently:

#### Fullstack development

- Node.js (JavaScript runtime environment for building scalable network applications)
- · Next.js (React framework for server-side rendering and static site generation)
- o TailwindCSS (utility-first CSS framework for building custom designs quickly)
- Framer Motion (animation library for creating fluid UI transitions and interactions)
- Three.js (JavaScript library for creating 3D graphics in the browser)

#### · Web3/Blockchain

- Solidity (smart contract programming language for Ethereum and other blockchains)
- o Truffle (development framework for Ethereum smart contracts)
- Hardhat (development environment for building and testing smart contracts on Ethereum and other blockchains)
- Remix (browser-based IDE for smart contract development and testing)
- o Metamask (browser extension for interacting with Ethereum and other blockchains)
- OpenZeppelin (library for secure smart contract development)
- · Chainlink (decentralized oracle network for securely connecting smart contracts to off-chain data sources)
- · Aave (smart contracts for innovative approaches to DeFi)

#### · Network Security

- o Utilizing the OSI model
- Firewall configuration and management
- Vulnerability assessment and management
- OWASP Top 10 web application security risks
- o Penetration testing (including tools found in Kali Linux)

## **Employment history**

### Developer, Free Lancer. Asheville, North Carolina Feb. 2022 - Present

Freelance programmer and IT specialist. Primary focus on building amazing UI/UX using next-gen tech for demanding clients.

- Previous clients include non-profit organizations such as OurVoice NC and private contractors. Related skills are as follows:
  - Utilizing the latest web technologies, including React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Firebase, AWS, and more!
  - · Assisting clients build and redesign network infrastructure.
  - Updating client knowledge and skills to keep up with rapid advancements in computer technology and security.
  - Programming of low-level embedded microprocessors using CircuitPython.
  - Providing technical support to designers, marketing and sales departments, suppliers, engineers, and other team members throughout product development and implementation processes.
  - Testing and verifying hardware and support peripherals to ensure compliance with demanding specifications and requirements.
  - Designing and developing computer hardware and support peripherals, support logic, microprocessors, custom integrated circuits, etc.

### IT Support Specialist, SCW Security. Asheville, NC 2016 - 2022

Customer support technician. The main focus is to interact directly with end-users and deliver customer satisfaction.

- Job requirements:
  - o Communicating directly with end users.
  - Providing remote support using software like GoToAssist & TeamViewer.
  - $\bullet \quad \text{Helping train machine learning models for proprietary CV software}. \\$
  - Diagnosing network and device problems and implementing technical or procedural solutions.
  - o Resolving customer complaints regarding sales and service.
  - Review damage reports, prepare or review repair cost estimates, and plan work to be performed.

### Educational Finance Loan Agent, Sitel. Asheville, NC Jan. 2015 - Mar. 2016

Sitel is a global call center company providing customer experience management solutions to various industries. It has operations in 25+ countries and employs over 90,000 associates worldwide.

- Call center representative. Focused on taking customer applications for student loans and guiding them through the process.
- Prepare, examine, and analyze accounting records, financial statements, and other financial reports to determine eligibility for education loans.
- Assist students and/or their co-signer through loan processes.
- Being an intermediary between loanees, banks, and contract underwriters.
- Providing telecommunication correspondence for loanees throughout the loan process

#### Warehouse Specialist, Sunshine Employment. Asheville, NC 2008 - 2015

Factory/warehouse savant. Main duties are wide-ranging warehousing tasks including:

- Shipping & Receiving, Collation between departments, machine operations, industrial printing, packing, and QA.
- Operate equipment to verify operational efficiency.
- Operation of high-cost production equipment to meet production demands in a timely manner.
- Inspect, test, and adjust completed units to ensure that units meet specifications, tolerances, and customer order requirements.
- Calibrating parts to determine tolerances, using precision measuring instruments such as micrometers, calipers, and verniers.

## Education

- The Internet
  - My most valuable learning resource. Thousands of hours reviewing documentation, RFCs, Improvement Proposals, Videos, coding challenges, etc.
    Always learning more!
- Asheville Buncombe Technical College, Asheville, North Carolina
  - GED, General Education with focus on computer science, 2006